Guide to the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Biomedical Communications Department records, 1973-1996
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Biomedical Communications Department records, 1973-1996
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Biomedical Communications Department records, 1973-1996
24-14-3352
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Biomedical Communications
3.6 cubic ft.
Photographs, negatives and contact sheets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs, negatives and contact sheets maintained by the Biomedical Communications Department of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Cornell University, from 1973 to 1996.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Biomedical Communications Department of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Cornell University, was created in the 1970s. It was the photography department for the College, and the precursor to the Image Lab. It was dissolved in 1995.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs, negatives and contact sheets maintained by the Biomedical Communications Department of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Cornell University, from 1973 to 1996.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. Biomedical Communications.
Subjects:
Veterinary Medicine--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Negatives.; Contact sheets.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Administrative Files
Box: 1
One folder of material about the Biomedical Communications Department. Includes a log for orders taken from 1980-1994.
Series II. Photo Files by Animal
Box: 1
Mostly photographic prints, many produced by Cornell University Photography, David Grunfeld, and other photographers. Dates range from ca. 1975-1985.
Series III. Photo Files by Photographer
Box: 2
Mostly contact sheets, arranged by photographer. Most are from David Grunfeld or Cornell University Photography. The bulk of the material is from 1974-1986.
Series IV. Photo Files by Class
Boxes: 2-3
Negatives, contact sheets, and some prints, for individual class photos and composites. There are also class lists and other associated paper materials. Class years covered include 1981-1998.
Series V. Photo Files by Topic/Event/Client
Boxes: 3-4
Mostly negatives, a few contact sheets and prints. Arranged alphabetically by client name, topic or event. The negatives in Box 4, folder 15 have no subjects indicated but are arranged by order number. Subjects and/or clients can be identified by cross referencing with the order log in Series I, Administrative Files.
Series VI. Slides
Boxes: 4-5
Sets of slides in multiple slide boxes, arranged by topic.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Administrative Files
  - Administrative Information and Order Log, ca. 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Photo Files by Animal
  - Aquavet, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beef Cattle, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Birds (pet), ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Birds (wild), ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Buffalo, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cats, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cats in Clinic, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chickens, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cows, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cows - Clinic/Classroom, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cows - Dairy, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Deer, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dogs, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dogs, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dogs in Clinics, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dogs in Clinics, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dogs - Ophthalmology, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Donkeys, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ferrets, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Foxes (Dr. Moise), ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Geese, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Goats, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Guinea Pigs, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hamster, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Horses, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Horses, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Horses, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Horses at Park, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Horses on Park Track, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Horses - Mares and Foals, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Horses - Hospital, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Horses - Wild, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Horses - CEM quarantine, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Lab Animals, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Llamas, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mice, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Monkeys, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pigs, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Rabbits, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Raccoons, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Reptiles, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Sheep, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Shellfish, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Wolf, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Woodchucks, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Zoo Animals, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Series III. Photo Files by Photographer
  - Doody, David M - Contacts and Negs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, ca. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, ca. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Grunfeld, David - Contacts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gwaltney - Contacts and Negs, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Peltzman, J. - Contacts and Negs, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reis, John - Contacts, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reis, John - Zoo and Wildlife Symposium - Contacts and Prints, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - University Photo - Contacts, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - University Photo - Contacts and Negs, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Unknown - Contacts, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Unknown - Contacts, 1982-1983, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series IV. Photo Files by Class
  - Class Composites for Linda Ritzler, Continuing Education - Classes 1943-1968, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Class of 1981 (Jean Feldman only), ca. 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Class of 1982 - negs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Class of 1983 - composite neg, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Class of 1984, ca. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Class of 1984 - negs, ca. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Class of 1984 - negs, ca. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Class of 1985 - negs, ca. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Class of 1986 - negs, ca. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Class of 1987 - Composite negs, ca. 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Class of 1987 - negs, ca. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Class of 1988, ca. 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Class of 1988 - negs, ca. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Class of 1989 - composite and miscellaneous, ca. 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Class of 1989 - negs, ca. 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Class of 1989 - negs, ca. 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1990 - contact sheets, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Class of 1990 - negs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1990 - negs, ca. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Class of 1990 - negs, ca. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Class of 1990 - Miscellaneous, ca. 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Class of 1991 - contacts and negs, ca. 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Class of 1991 - contacts and negs, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Class of 1991 - contacts and negs, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Class of 1992 - negs, ca. 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Class of 1992 - package negs (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Class of 1992 - package negs (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Class of 1992 - identified negs (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Class of 1993, ca. 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Class of 1994, ca. 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Class of 1995, ca. 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Class of 1996, ca. 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Class of 1997, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Class of 1998, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified Class Pictures - negs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Series V. Photo Files by Topic/Event/Client
  - Aerial Photos, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Conference, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Annual Conference, January 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual Conference, January 1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Annual Conference?, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Aquavet/Snakes - Rickard/McNamara/Bigelow - negs and slides, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Biomedical Communications Staff (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Building Drawings, Photos and Painting (Ned Trethaway/Public Affairs), 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Buildings - Construction, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Buildings - Construction, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Buildings - Miscellaneous negs, ca. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "The Canine Eye" poster, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Coggins, Matthews - Pathology - EIA antigen, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - CVM Logo, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Diagnostic Lab - Brochure - negs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Donkeys breeding - Antczak - slides negs and contacts, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Farriery - Buster Conklin - negs, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Francis Fox (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gordon Woods, Rockefeller Farm - Embryo Transplant, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Ground Breaking, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Halloween, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Dr. Hillman delivering foal - negs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Horses - Equine Research Park? - negs, ca. 1980s (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Nita Jager, 1979, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Large Animal Clinic Surgery - Collier - negs, slides and contacts, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - McGregor Paste-ups - "Research Now and Then", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Dean Melby/Wayne Griffith Plaque Presentation, October 1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Mobile Veterinary Clinic, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Pathology Department, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Physiology - Sheep Brain Surgery - Bergman - negs, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Plaques - PR Photos, April 1988 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Poisonous Plants - Mary Smith - negs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Poisonous Plants - Mary Smith - negs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Dr. Postle, 1973, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Presentation to President Dale Corson, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Reunion - Alumni Group Shots, June 1985 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Reunion, June 1986 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Saratoga - Audrey Lowe photos - negs, August 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Saratoga - Audrey Lowe photos - negs, August 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Saratoga - Travers Parade and Ball - negs, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Saratoga - Travers Parade and Ball - negs and contact sheets, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Fred Scott - portraits - negs, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Small Animal Clinic - Dog Procedures - Kirk, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Small Animal Clinic - Ophthalmology - Riis, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Robert Smith, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Student Group, Q Barn, July 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Terrier Field Days, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Trethaway, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Trotter - Spine Paste-up Record, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous prints and negs, ca. 1973-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous negs, ca. 1973-1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Negs by Order Number, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series VI. Slides
  - Buildings and Grounds, ca. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Aquatic, ca. 1975-1985 (Box 5)
  - Birds, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Cats, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Cats, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Cats, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Cats, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Cows, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Dogs, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Exotics, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Snakes, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Small Animals, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Horses, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Aquavet, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Dogs and Cats - procedures, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Horses - procedures, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Students, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Students of Color, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Faculty (alpha), ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Faculty - no i.d., ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Baker Institute, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Dean Melby's Retirement, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Open House, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Halloween, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Historical, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Anatomy, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Computers, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Microscopes, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Radiology, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Surgery, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Buildings - Exteriors, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Buildings - Interiors, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Library, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Barns, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Equine Research Park, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Clinics, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - Labs, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)
  - India, ca. 1975-1995 (Box 5)